Ip Siu Kei, Gary

Summary

Hands-on Java developer with 10+ years' experience in application development including financial software development. I work for various organizations in different fields including Education, Software Vendor, Telco and Financial Institution. Now I am a front office developer, responsible for a client-facing fund trading platform serving HK and TW customers.



Language proficiency: native Chinese (Cantonese), fluent English, working professional Mandarin

Mobile: +852 9156 1302 Email: skip@graduate.hku.hk

LinkedIn: https://hk.linkedin.com/in/garyip

Specialties

Java (Core, Concurrency, Collections), Spring Framework, Hibernate, HTML5, AngularJS, Oracle DB, MuleESB, Linux, bash, Maven, SVN, Git

Education

2003 – 2005: MSc in Computer Science, The University of Hong Kong

2000 – 2003: BEng in Software Engineering, 2nd Class Honours (Division One), The University of Hong Kong

Certificates

Sun Certified Enterprise Architect (**SCEA**); Sun Certified Programmer for the Java 2 Platform 1.4 (**SCJP**); Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 8 Programmer (**OCAJP8**)

Honours and Awards

JPMorgan Change & Co. - 2015 Java Certification Program Awardee

Experience

2016 - present: Senior Associate, Asset Management, JPMorgan Chase & Co.

eTrading platform of JPMorgan Funds for HK and TW customers

- Participating in the development revamped version of HK eTrading platform www.jpmorganam.com.hk, using Spring Framework, Hibernate ORM, JPA, RESTful, AngularJS, jQuery, HTML5
- Application Security Champion, responsible for application security and control assessments, coordinates regular security scanning (dynamic, static code and open sources libraries)
- Working with Architect team to implement the eTrading platform with firm-wide approved technologies and standards

2009 – 2016: Senior Associate, Corporate and Investment Bank, JPMorgan Chase & Co.

Liquidity solutions system for 50+ branches across APAC, EMEA and WHEM

- Development Lead, Leading the development of the critical message-oriented middleware that interfacing 70+ firm-wide partner systems, using JMS, Spring Framework, MuleESB, WebsphereMQ
- Application Manager, coordinates teamwork and manages my 4 direct reports
- Negotiate new functionalities, change requests and delivery timelines with business product owners, operators and Business Analysts

2008 – 2009: Application Developer, Worldwide Securities Services, JPMorgan Chase & Co.

Participating in the design and development of India and Taiwan Sub-Custodian projects

- Participating in the development of Indian Sub-Custodian project, using Spring Framework, Hibernate ORM, JSP and Yahoo! User Interface (YUI) Library
- Participating in the enhancement and provide L3 support for Taiwan Sub-Custodian system
- Production change management, coordinate delivery within business users and supporting team for production rollout

2007 - 2008: Application Developer, Treasury Services, JPMorgan Chase & Co.

Design and development of Regulatory Reporting Repository (RCube) System

- Design and developed the Rcube system, using Spring Framework, Hibernate ORM, JSP. Successfully rolled out for India branch
- Worked closely with operations team to capture user requirements and features requests
- Coordinate delivery and supporting team for production roll out

2006 – 2007: Senior Application Developer, CASCADE Limited, subsidiary of PCCW

Participating in the design and development of revamped IPTV middleware

- Lead developer, design and developed the revamped version of IPTV middleware, using Spring Framework,
 Spring Webflow, Hibernate ORM, JPA
- Support Pre-sales team for various foreign countries projects
- PoC work on new tools and frameworks, provide knowledge sharing sessions with team members

2005 – 2006: Consultant, CORE Consulting Limited

Participating in the development of company flagship document exchange platform - iDEX

- Participating in the enhancement of iDEX, a web-based document exchange platform written in Java Servlet, JSP, Struts, HTML, JavaScript
- Working closely with customization team for new features and requirement
- Lead developer, leads and provides training sessions for offshore (Zhuhai) development team

2003 - 2005: Assistant Computer Officer, Center for Information Security and Cryptography, CS, HKU

Participating in research and development works on Information Security projects

- Participating in the development of Digital Evidence Search Kit written in Java Swing, JNI (sponsored by HKPF)
- QA testing support for an internal developed video streaming encryption software written in C++
- Configured and delivered a multi-lingo search engine for a free access legal information website HKLII http://www.hklii.hk

Membership

Professional member of The British Computer Society

Hobbies

Reading, Blogging, Child Care, Soccer, Building LEGO, Investment